<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gov1347 Election Analytics Blog</title>
    <link>https://username.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Gov1347 Election Analytics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://username.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: The Ground Game</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-18-week-6-the-ground-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-18-week-6-the-ground-game/</guid>
      <description>The Ground Game This week’s focus is on mobilization of voters and how voter turnout may have an impact on who does well in elections. Most often, campaigns will focus on turning out those who are infrequent voters that align well with their party and or candidate’s platform. Methods include texting, calling, and knocking on potential voter’s doors to get out the vote. One big question I will try to investigate is whether or not there’s a relationship between high turnout and the outcomes of either one of the major parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Ad Spend and Election Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-08-week-5-ads-and-election-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-08-week-5-ads-and-election-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will investigate the effects that ad spending can have on the outcome of elections on a district by district level. Using my current model, I will incorporate data found on the FEC’s website to approximate ad spend on a campaign district level. Using how much money was spent will be my variable, though I am aware that some scholarship says that number of ads rather than money spent is also a good indicator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Incumbancy and Election Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-01-week-4-incumbancy-and-election-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-01-week-4-incumbancy-and-election-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Expert Ratings In my previous blogs, I have focused solely at national variables and conditions which may affect our election outcomes. Things like GDP, unemployment, polling, etc. are very helpful tools but we also have the option to look at elections from a much closer, district level approach. On the district level, many experts watch and weigh in on important races. Organizations such as Cook Political Report and Sabato’s Crystal Ball take into account local conditions and determine ratings on an individual district level basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Polling and Elections </title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-25-week-3-polling-and-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-25-week-3-polling-and-elections/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This week, we focused on seeing how polling might affect and predict election outcomes. Gelman and King spoke about how polling is really only indicative of people’s preferences close to the election. Over the course of a campaign cycle, Gelman and King argue, responses to pollsters during the campaign are not generally informed or even, in a sense we describe, “rational.”
For this reason, when building and assessing a model this week, I will try to weigh the polls heavier when they are closer to the election day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Elections and the Economy</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-17-week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-17-week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</guid>
      <description>This weeks blog post will focus on using the economy as a variable to predictive modeling for the upcoming election using past data such as the unemployment rate, GDP for each quarter, RDI, etc.
Introduction There has been extensive research showing that prospective voters substantially consider the state of the economy when making electoral decisions. Christopher H. Achen’s and Larry M. Bartels in Democracy For Realists argue that voters use the economy as a way to measure the performance of an incumbent party / president.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Elections </title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-11-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-11-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>This is my first weekly election blog posting for an ongoing assignment for the class Election Analytics at Harvard College with Professor Ryan Enos. Enjoy! :)
I will be using the visualization customization extension for this blog post and will use the resulting data to make a prediction about the upcoming 2022 midterm election.
create a map of Republican/Democrat voteshare margin by state in a year of your choice, create a map of Republican/Democrat voteshare margin by state and congressional district in 2014, label each state (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
