<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy on Gov1347 Election Analytics Blog</title>
    <link>https://username.github.io/categories/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy on Gov1347 Election Analytics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://username.github.io/categories/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Incumbancy and Election Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-01-week-4-incumbancy-and-election-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-10-01-week-4-incumbancy-and-election-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Expert Ratings In my previous blogs, I have focused solely at national variables and conditions which may affect our election outcomes. Things like GDP, unemployment, polling, etc. are very helpful tools but we also have the option to look at elections from a much closer, district level approach. On the district level, many experts watch and weigh in on important races. Organizations such as Cook Political Report and Sabato’s Crystal Ball take into account local conditions and determine ratings on an individual district level basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Elections and the Economy</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-17-week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>youremail@domain.com (Janet Hernandez)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/2022-09-17-week-2-elections-and-the-economy/</guid>
      <description>This weeks blog post will focus on using the economy as a variable to predictive modeling for the upcoming election using past data such as the unemployment rate, GDP for each quarter, RDI, etc.
Introduction There has been extensive research showing that prospective voters substantially consider the state of the economy when making electoral decisions. Christopher H. Achen’s and Larry M. Bartels in Democracy For Realists argue that voters use the economy as a way to measure the performance of an incumbent party / president.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
